# Christopher Lehneis

EMAIL: cdlehneis@gmail.com

PHONE: 631.252.8117

GITHUB: http://github.com/SyntaxChris



#### **PROFILE**

Artist, Engineer, and Full Stack Web Developer. Military veteran and team player with a passion for expressing creativity with the latest web technologies. Strong desire to develop clean and intuitive Front End UI/UX designs. Prior experience with Automated Machining, Robotics, Prosthetics and Orthotics. Served over 5 years in the United States Coast Guard as a Lead Electronics Technician for Long Range Aids to Navigations.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Full Stack Web Developer, Dopamine Inc., New York, NY

8/2014-Present

- Responsible for developing gamified web applications from the ground up using Ruby (Ruby on Rails), Javascript (Angular JS, ¡Query), CSS3 (SASS), and HTML5.
- Experience implementing testing with Rspec and Jasmine.
- Integrates web applications with Postgres databases.
- Responsible for setting up Linux servers and Load Balancers (Digital Ocean) for staging and production environments on an Agile software development team.

## Training Coordinator, Learn CNC Machining Inc., Bohemia, NY 8/2013-4/2014

- Developed curriculums for Computer Numerical Controller (CNC) programing, Mastercam Computer Aided Design (CAD) software, and setup/operator training classes.
- Designed marketing material for featured software training programs.
- Trained up to 35 students per class, and provided customer support for troubleshooting CAD software.

### Field Service Engineer, Automation Solutions Inc., West Chester, PA 5/2012-3/2013

- Installed, serviced and programmed CNC machining centers for automated manufacturing at over 30 manufacturing companies on the east coast of the United States.
- Developed engineering procedures for field related installations and services.
- Implemented FANUC robotic servo arm systems for large scale automotive manufacturing companies.

# Christopher Lehneis

#### Orthotics Technician, Lehneis O & P Associates Ltd., Roslyn, NY 4/2008-12/2011

- Designed, fabricated, and fitted orthotic and prosthetic devices for patients.
- Integrated CAD software in orthotic and prosthetic designs.
- Managed inventory for all orthotic and prosthetic products and supplies.

#### Electronics Technician, United States Coast Guard, Cape May, NJ 2/2003-3/2008

- Search and Rescue Boat-crew Member at Station Castle Hill, Newport RI.
- High tower climber up to 650ft.
- Lead Electronics Technician responsible for supervising teams that upgraded over 30 Long Range Aids To Navigation (LORAN) stations throughout the United States.
- Received Coast Guard Special Operations Service Ribbon for diligent security operations during the 2004 Americas Cup in Newport Harbor.

### **EDUCATION**

The Flatiron School, Web Development Fellowship	8/2014
---	--------

12 week Web Development Immersive program + 12 week career internship

#### State University of New York at Stony Brook 5/2012

Bachelors of Applied Science, Technological Systems Management

# Thomas Edison State University 5/2008

Associates of Applied Science, Electronics Studies

#### **SKILLS**

Ruby	Ruby On Rails	Rspec	Postgres
Javascript	Angular JS	įQuery	SQL
CSS 3	SASS	Zurb Foundation	Bootstrap
Linux	Git/Github	NGINX	Agile Development
Illustrator	Photoshop	Electronics	CNC Machining